<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Larry G Wapnitsky</title>
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="larry.wapnitsky.com"/>
	<updated>2021-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
	<id></id>
	<author>
		<name>Larry G. Wapnitsky</name>
		<email></email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Chips of deception - Tteokbokki</title>
		<link href="/posts/2021-01-05-hot-chip-deception-tteokbokki/"/>
		<updated>2021-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>/posts/2021-01-05-hot-chip-deception-tteokbokki/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tteokbokki is well-known as a spicy Korean street food - long, tubular rice cakes with a sauce made traditionally from gochujang and anchove-based broth. Considering how spicy it can be served on the street, this snack, once I looked it up after buying it, should have been good and spicy. Even without looking it up, the picture of the smiling hot pepper on the front, and the inclusion of capsaicin powder in the ingredients should have been a good marker pointing to lots of spice. It even says &amp;quot;HOT SPICE&amp;quot; on the back!! Well...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/snacks/tteokbokki_back_800_rotated.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon opening the bag, there was a hint of spice, but nothing overpowering. Not a good sign to start. I poured some out and started to munch on them. If anything, there was more of a sweetness than a spiciness. I waited and, eventually, there was a little bit of spice, but nothing that warranted the &amp;quot;warning signs&amp;quot; from the labels. I gave some to my daughter, who doesn&#39;t like spice, and she really liked these...again, because of the sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I recommend thse? Only if you like sweet and spicy, leaning more toward the sweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess my next step is to learn how to recreate the real thing...not the crispy bagged snack. Once that happens, I&#39;ll be sure to update you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Weight Is Over...By A Lot</title>
		<link href="/posts/2021-01-04-the-weight-is-over/"/>
		<updated>2021-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>/posts/2021-01-04-the-weight-is-over/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Overall fitness improvement is the goal for not just this year, but the future in general. I&#39;m not going to set time- or weight-specific goals, as those have caused me to struggle mentally in the past. What I DO want to do is lower my weight to a more healthy range and get my physical activity back up to a reasonable state so that I can be active without getting tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this combined starts today,  January 4th, 2021 (well, actually last night). I began doing intermittent fasting again using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zerofasting.com/&quot;&gt;Zero&lt;/a&gt; as my tracker and guide. I have my fitness apps all set to go, as well as videos I&#39;ve made note of on YouTube. In addition, I&#39;ve already spoken to the guys in my accountability group, and we&#39;re all in this together. I believe that last part is what&#39;s going to really push me through this year, as the intent is to really be accountable to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&#39;s plan - continue my fast and get a little exercise and meditation in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you plan to follow me on this journey, don&#39;t expect the use of the word &lt;em&gt;diet&lt;/em&gt; or specific mentions of actual body weight. What you can expect is to see updates on how I&#39;m feeling mentally about the physical changes and (hopeful) improvements that are coming. Drop me a line on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lgwapnitsky&quot;&gt;@lgwapnitsky&lt;/a&gt; with words of encouragement, inspiration, or if you want accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/8y8NVqFqhTQVa&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/ratatouille-admin-billy-boyd-8y8NVqFqhTQVa&quot;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A Very Happy New Year To You</title>
		<link href="/posts/2021-01-01-Happy-New-Year/"/>
		<updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>/posts/2021-01-01-Happy-New-Year/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Without going into too much detail, the past year-plus has been very difficult for me. My fitness has waned significantly, my mental acuity has suffered, and I&#39;ve just not felt very self-confident. I&#39;m sure many others have felt this with the overwhelming power that COVID-19 has had over our society. I&#39;m not saying I&#39;m a unique butterfly, but my issues are mine to address, and only mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;physical-fitness&quot;&gt;Physical Fitness &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#physical-fitness&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many races were postponed or cancelled in 2020 due to the pandemic. Combined with a lack of mental energy, I completely fell off in my workout routines, gained some weight (which I did try to work on and made some progress regarding loss), and have physically changed back to an uncomfortable level. I did try to lean on my social groups, but this proved to be difficult to manage, even though we were accountable to each other. As a runner, and general fitness guy, this has not sat well with me, and I need a good kick in the butt to get going again. How? More accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m going to lay myself bare, here. I&#39;m going to update you on my physical progress as the year goes on. While it may not be frequent, I&#39;ll try at least once per month to let you know where I am in terms of setting/following a routine and how I&#39;m feeling. If I fall short on posting, call me out on social media. If I&#39;m slacking off and losing motivation, call me out on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the goal is to use my physical fitness to build routines that will eventually help build and improve on my...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mental-fitness&quot;&gt;Mental Fitness &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#mental-fitness&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that managing my mental fitness in 2020 has been a tough row to hoe is an understatement. I struggled with keeping my mind active, trying to read, avoiding useless video media, and wasting time on the Internet. I know that I can do better, it&#39;s just a matter of setting the habits and goals, then sticking to them. Much like physical fitness, I need the accountability and tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to journal this year, then gave up within a matter of days. The book is sitting by my bedside. Restart it? Use the blog as a &amp;quot;journal&amp;quot; of sorts? Possibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a lot of work ahead in order to regain the fitness I once had, much like my physical fitness. Will I ever be the same? Probably not. Can I be a better version of who I&#39;ve been for the past year? Definitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-growth-%26-education&quot;&gt;Personal Growth &amp;amp; Education &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#personal-growth-%26-education&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I&#39;ll review my past goals and set some new ones here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many cooking-related goals to review and set:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grilling and smoking - I learned to make pastrami this year. That was an adventure, and pretty darned delicious. Beyond that, I just smoked meats when I felt like it, but didn&#39;t quite do enough. So, for 2021, the goal is to smoke more more meat AND to continue building my own smoker (soon to be written about in The Lab), which coincides with another goal for the year that will be mentioned below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CEudcFtHmGe&quot;&gt;https://www.instagram.com/p/CEudcFtHmGe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sous-vide and pickling went hand-in-hand, as I used my SV for pickling, as well as some delicious fish, scallops, and beautiful strip steaks. Again, the goal is to do more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pressure cooker has been my go-to for a few years, now, and this year I really picked up on some new dishes that became family favorites - meatloaf &amp;amp; mashed potatoes, pork belly with shoyu eggs, and more. 2021 is the year of learning to bake in the pressure cooker. I&#39;ve tried once with middling success. I REALLY want to make a cheesecake!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just keep cooking! It&#39;s fun, I&#39;m learning a lot, especially with baking AND the fact that my son is gluten-free, so adjusting for that has been an adventure in learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-learn programming - why? Well, for one, I need it for my smoker. I&#39;m combining a few projects and building a smoker out of a file-cabinet, then adding in a temperature regulated heater to manage the smoke temperature. As of writing this, I&#39;m 75% done with the cabinet, and about 80% with the electronics. The latter is the tougher part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to meet my Goodreads reading goal this year, with a few cheat books included that I read to my daughter. I don&#39;t see an option for a 2021 challenge, but my plan is to either meet or exceed the 52 books completed in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;gr_challenge_11621&quot; style=&quot;border: 2px solid #EBE8D5; border-radius:10px; padding: 0px 7px 0px 7px; max-width:230px; min-height: 100px&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div id=&quot;gr_challenge_progress_body_11621&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 12px; font-family: georgia,serif;line-height: 18px&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 4px 0 10px; font-weight: normal; text-align: center&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-family:georgia,serif;font-style:italic; font-size: 1.1em&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/challenges/11621-2020-reading-challenge&quot;&gt;2020 Reading Challenge&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h3&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;challengePic&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/challenges/11621-2020-reading-challenge&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 Reading Challenge&quot; style=&quot;float:left; margin-right: 10px; border: 0 none&quot; src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/challenges/1575497947p2/11621.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/1656256-larry&quot;&gt;Larry&lt;/a&gt; has
            completed his goal of reading
            50 books in
            2020!
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div style=&quot;width: 100px; margin: 4px 5px 5px 0; float: left; border: 1px solid #382110; height: 8px; overflow: hidden; background-color: #FFF&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&quot;width: 100%; background-color: #D7D2C4; float: left&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;visibility:hidden&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div style=&quot;font-family: arial, verdana, helvetica, sans-serif;font-size:90%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/19222365&quot;&gt;52 of 50 (100%)&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 10px;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/19222365&quot;&gt;view books&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;script src=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/widget/1656256-larry?challenge_id=11621&amp;v=2&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-of-the-iceberg&quot;&gt;Tip of the Iceberg &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;#tip-of-the-iceberg&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only just the beginning. 2021 is really the year I want to make changes, as well as be mindful of and accountable to them. I hope you&#39;ll join me on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Chips Are On The Table/Hot Tikha Ganthia</title>
		<link href="/posts/2020-12-22-the-chips-are-on-the-table/"/>
		<updated>2020-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>/posts/2020-12-22-the-chips-are-on-the-table/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite types of place to shop is ethnic supermarkets. I had a need for a lot of very specific ingredients for some cooking that I was going, so I schlepped to my local Indian market to grab what I needed. While wandering around, I stubmled into the snack aisle and became overwhelmed with the selection of interesting flavors. One type of flavor that always sticks out to me (and will become somewhat of a running theme) is hot and spicy. So when I saw bags upon bags of spicy snacks, I knew that I had to try something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some browsing at the amazing selection, I decided on a bag of Tikha Ganthia. These are spicy little chickpea flour noodles. They looked like crunchy, curvy sticks of flavor, and I was sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/snacks/tikha_ganthia_bag.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opened the bag when I got home to have with lunch, and I knew that, from aroma alone, I was going to like these. There was a warm spiciness that I&#39;ve come to expect from good quality Indian food. I poured some into a bowl, and dug in. These are defintely not the snacks we&#39;re used to here in the United States.  The use of chickpea flour is also unique to my tastebuds for snacks.  The crunch was subdued, but had the perfect amount of mouth-feel. The flavor, while spicy, was not overwhelming. Then again, I have a hot pallette and usually eat hotter than normal foods that my family doesn&#39;t care for (bonus, these chips are now all mine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/snacks/tikha_ganthia_bowl_HDR.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I buy these again? In a heartbeat.&lt;br&gt;
Would I recommend them? Absolutely!&lt;br&gt;
Am I going to try to learn how to make a homemade version? Time will tell...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>I&#39;m back to blogging</title>
		<link href="/posts/2020-12-15-back-to-blogging/"/>
		<updated>2020-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>/posts/2020-12-15-back-to-blogging/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Overall, it should be good for my mind to wipe away the cobwebs and be creative. But what&#39;s been keeping me from writing all this time, and what plans do I have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t really decided on a single path, but there&#39;s be a good mix of cooking and food stuff, technology, my journey back into fitness, home projects, and more. There&#39;s so much in my mind that it&#39;s tough to figure out exactly where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, short post to (re)start things off, but I really hope to keep myself on track this time and keep blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larry&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
