<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Larry G. Wapnitsky</title>
	<subtitle></subtitle>
	<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/"/>
	<updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Larry G. Wapnitsky</name>
		<email>Larry@Wapnitsky.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Shouting into the void?</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2022-03-11-first-post-long-time/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/shoutintovoid.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/shoutintovoid.pnd"/>
		<updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2022-03-11-first-post-long-time/</id>
		<summary>It&#39;s almost a year since I&#39;ve posted. Going to restart, really, but who&#39;s going to pay attention?</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been a slacker. It&#39;s been almost a year since I&#39;ve posted, and I have no real good excuse, beyond health and some mental struggles :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I need to get better at this, even if nobody is reading. That&#39;s why I&#39;m going to put blogging into my schedule. Whether it&#39;s a personal update, plain BS, or something from my computer lab or kitchen, I&#39;m going to post it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoepfully someone out there is reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best,&lt;br /&gt;
Larry&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Why have I been so quiet?</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-04-28-why-so-quiet/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/neck_mri.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/neck_mri.png"/>
		<updated>2021-04-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-04-28-why-so-quiet/</id>
		<summary>I know I said I&#39;d post more, but there&#39;s been a lot going on since the last post...</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I know I said I&#39;d post more, but there&#39;s been a lot going on since my &lt;a href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-05-the-slackers-health-update&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the injury I previously wrote about got worse. After seeing my excellent sports doctor, the diagnosis of my pinched nerve turned out to be a degrading disk in my neck, as shown by an MRI. The recommendation was to see a surgeon for a consult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I did. The PA that came in first wanted to just have an epidural done. I let her know that steroids and I don&#39;t really get along too well. The doctor came in, complimented me on my bushy beard saying, &amp;quot;That&#39;s going to hide the surgery scar pretty well!&amp;quot;. Hence, we discussed an anterior cervical fusion on C5-C6. C4-C5 and C6-C7 are also degrading, but not as bad right now, so we&#39;re minimizing the surgigcal procedure, which is scheduled for May 5th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not looking forward to surgery, but at the same time, I am, as I want to be able to play with my kids, pick them up, exercise. This inactivity (save for some walking) and my bad diet have not been too good for me. Here&#39;s hoping that all the pain goes away after a few weeks of recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;side-note&quot;&gt;Side Note &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-04-28-why-so-quiet/#side-note&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ignore MOST of the stuff below, except for the Matrix chat link. I&#39;ll have a post about Matrix later on, and how to get in touch with me there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m also slowly migrating away from Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The others were a failed experiment at using some federated services. I may try again at a later date, but it&#39;s not a priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;A post will be coming at a later date, but I&#39;m simultaneously expanding and contracting my social presence. Feel free to hit me up on the regular channels, as well as the new ones. Here&#39;s where I can be found:&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;chat&quot;&gt;Chat &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-04-28-why-so-quiet/#chat&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@lgwapnitsky:matrix.wapnitsky.com (preferred)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;s&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://telegram.me/larrygwapnitsky&quot;&gt;https://telegram.me/larrygwapnitsky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;#### Social Sites ####&lt;/s&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;s&gt;@lgwapnitsky@friendica.wapnitsky.com&lt;/s&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;s&gt;@lgwapnitsky@toot.wapnitsky.com&lt;/s&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;s&gt;@lgwapnitsky@pod.wapnitsky.com&lt;/s&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;s&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lgwapnitsky&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/lgwapnitsky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/s&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;s&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/larry.g.wapnitsky&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/larry.g.wapnitsky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;#### Images/videos ####&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;@lgwapnitsky@pixelfed.wapnitsky.com&lt;/s&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;s&gt;@lgwapnitsky@peertube.wapnitsky.com&lt;/s&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;s&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/larrygwapnitsky&quot;&gt;https://instagram.com/larrygwapnitsky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;The website will be updated with these very soon.&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>E-mail issues for wapnitsky.com</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-11-email-issues/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/7360483-simpsons-technical-difficulties1.jpg"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/7360483-simpsons-technical-difficulties1.jpg"/>
		<updated>2021-03-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-11-email-issues/</id>
		<summary>If you&#39;re trying to contact anyone at wapnitsky.com, there is currently an email issue...</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;issue-resolved-at-9%3A30-am-2021-03-11&quot;&gt;Issue resolved at 9:30 AM 2021-03-11 &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-11-email-issues/#issue-resolved-at-9%3A30-am-2021-03-11&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a network issue, email to anyone at &lt;a href=&quot;http://wapnitsky.com/&quot;&gt;Wapnitsky.com&lt;/a&gt; is currently down. If you need to get a hold of me, please use &lt;a href=&quot;https://telegram.me/larrygwapnitsky&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt; in the meantime until there is a resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/images/posts/no-email.jpe&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for updates.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The slacker&#39;s health update</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-05-the-slackers-health-update/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/slacker.jpg"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/slacker.jpg"/>
		<updated>2021-03-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-05-the-slackers-health-update/</id>
		<summary>I haven&#39;t posted in month, even though I said I&#39;d be more on the ball. Why? Keep reading...</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a tough row to hoe for the past month or so (yet, my poetry skills still seem on point). I&#39;ve been dealing with a new injury which, in turn, has made it very tough for me to exercise. Combine that with my ongoing mental healing, I&#39;ve not been eating well and have gained a bit of weight. Let&#39;s just say I&#39;m not happy with it. Add to that a blood test that shows that I need to be a bit more careful moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The injury itself makes it very tough to sit at a computer and type for long periods of time. Even sitting in one position is painful after a while. I&#39;ve been in PT for a few weeks and, even though I think my therapist is trying to kill me, there is definitely improvement. I&#39;m hoping that the next few weeks show a significant increase in mobility and decrease in pain so that I can get back on the horse (or, in this case, the bike, for which I just purchased an indoor stand - more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to friends and family with their support, I&#39;m doing ok, and the road to wellness will be walked on again very soon. In the meantime, I&#39;ve a few articles stashed away that I&#39;ll be posting soon, so keep an eye out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Amcrest ASH21 Camera Review</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-01-Amcrest-ASH21-White-review/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/amcrestash21-w.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/amcrestash21-w.png"/>
		<updated>2021-03-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-01-Amcrest-ASH21-White-review/</id>
		<summary>I was recently given the opportunity to review the Amcrest ASH21 WiFi Camera. Here are my thoughts on the product.</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back when the pandemic started, I upgraded one of my webcams to one made by &lt;a href=&quot;https://amcrest.com/&quot;&gt;Amcrest&lt;/a&gt;. I was very satisifed with it. Since then, I&#39;ve been given the opportunity to test products from Amcrest, the most recent being the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0821Q23GF/ref=twister_B08HPKJBTB&quot;&gt;ASH21 WiFi Camera&lt;/a&gt;. This little monitor is a great device to have around. Let&#39;s take a brief look at the specs, pros, and cons of the ASH21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;specs&quot;&gt;Specs &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-01-Amcrest-ASH21-White-review/#specs&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolution -  1080p (1920x1080)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viewing Angle 93° Wide-View&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Night Vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special Modes
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baby Monitor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage Options
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud ($$)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MicroSD (up to 256GB, sold separately)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros&quot;&gt;Pros &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-01-Amcrest-ASH21-White-review/#pros&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to set up. Using the Android app, I had the camera up and running in a matter of minutes with no issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small and unobtrusive. This can be placed almost anywhere and not be in the way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good quality video and image capture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons&quot;&gt;Cons &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-01-Amcrest-ASH21-White-review/#cons&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App sometimes didn&#39;t connect immediately when on the same WiFi network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pan/Tilt controls can react a little slowly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio is decent, but not great. Then again, this isn&#39;t a high-level video camera used for production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-03-01-Amcrest-ASH21-White-review/#summary&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d definitely add more of these to my home. It&#39;s a great way of monitoring at a low cost. For me, I sometimes use it in my laundry room, where the slop sink tends to overflow during a wash (that&#39;s a whole other issue).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Telegram - What is it, and why do I use it?</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-28-telegram-and-why-i-use-it/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/600px-Telegram_logo.svg.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/600px-Telegram_logo.svg.png"/>
		<updated>2021-01-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-28-telegram-and-why-i-use-it/</id>
		<summary>In many of my posts, I mention that you can contact me through Telegram. What is Telegram? Why do I use it, and why should you?</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recent events regarding social media, many users have been switching to &lt;a href=&quot;https://telegram.me/&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt; for their instant messaging needs and social media output. Media outlets have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/363143&quot;&gt;reporting&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.igadgetsworld.com/10-reasons-to-switch-to-telegram/&quot;&gt;why&lt;/a&gt; to switch for weeks. But why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, personally, have been using Telegram since about 2013, and have watched it grow. I&#39;ve had friends join intermittently, and am slowly encouraging more to join, especially those who are using WhatsApp. Why? Security features (though some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/zakdoffman/2021/01/23/stop-using-signal-and-telegram-until-you-change-settings-after-whatsapp-and-imessage-privacy-backlash/&quot;&gt;aren&#39;t enabled by default&lt;/a&gt;) are a big component over regular social networks. Additionally, your data isn&#39;t shared amongst multiple platforms, unlke WA, which shares with Facebook, Instagram, and any other Facebook-owned network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/images/posts/telegram_desktop.png&quot; alt=&quot;Telegram Desktop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telegram is nice in that you can create groups that function in similar ways to Facebook groups and/or messenger chats. You have the ability (with a little bit of work) to automate responses using &amp;quot;bots&amp;quot; (more on this in a future article).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the bottom of my post, you can see that I&#39;m even using Telegram for comments on my articles. Even though you use a phone number for a login, I never see that data. It is encrypted between you and the Telegram server. (I also have my site data encrypted using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ssl.com/faqs/faq-what-is-ssl/&quot;&gt;SSL&lt;/a&gt;, so there&#39;s that layer of protection, too).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only my simple, cursory overview of Telegram. There&#39;s much more to learn about how it works. I&#39;ll be sure to post more about those in the future, but the articles mentioned above have plenty of good information as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, feel free to comment below, or contact me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://telegram.me/larrygwapnitsky&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lgwapnitsky&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Road To Fitness</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-22-road-to-fitness/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/health/pothole_road.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/health/pothole_road.png"/>
		<updated>2021-01-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-22-road-to-fitness/</id>
		<summary>The struggle bus has gotten back on the road, and I&#39;m back in the game to work on my fitness levels - both physical and mental. What&#39;s changed?</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To quote the &lt;a href=&quot;https://whitesnake.com/&quot;&gt;Whitesnake&lt;/a&gt; song &amp;quot;Here I Go Again&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I don&#39;t know where I&#39;m going
But I sure know where I&#39;ve been
Hanging on the promises
In songs of yesterday

And I&#39;ve made up my mind
I ain&#39;t wasting no more time

Here I go again
Here I go again
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-14-pause-and-effect/&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; about my fitness levels, I mentioned that I had already lost my gusto for fitness at the beginning of the year due to mental and physical fatigue. After hearing from a number of people (my accountability group, friends and associates online), I decided to turn up the dial again, set some goals, and re-restart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, my food intake. I let myself go near the end of 2020, thinking I could manage things myself. That did not work out well. I&#39;m back to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayoclinic.org/healthy-lifestyle/nutrition-and-healthy-eating/expert-answers/intermittent-fasting/faq-20441303&quot;&gt;Intermittent Fasting&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zerofasting.com/&quot;&gt;Zero Fasting&lt;/a&gt; platform. I&#39;m starting off slowly, with 16/8 split, with plans to eventually move back to 18/6. Right now, I usually hit 17 hours (or close to it) on a daily basis, and I&#39;m trying to be better about the quality of the foods I eat. One thing I like about IF is that once I start my daily fast, there&#39;s no room for snacking/desserts/etc. This takes will-power and control -- things I definitely need to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding exercise, I&#39;m using my &amp;quot;home gym&amp;quot; more. I&#39;ve my bosu ball, two Swiss balls, two sets of elastic resistance bands. YouTube has been great for finding easy workouts for all this equipment. Some even combine the equipment so that I&#39;m getting multiple benefits. The goal is to do these workouts at least 3 days a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, there&#39;s the dreadmill. I&#39;m not running outside right now, even though I love the weather. I need to be able to stop as needed, so indoors is the best thing for me. Rather than just hop on and go for a random run, I&#39;ve set a time/distance goal for June. Using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://beta.trainasone.com/register?referrer_token=k7Jjvn3c9ZgzhvXLMXSG&quot;&gt;TrainAsOne&lt;/a&gt; app as my guide, workouts are generated for me for at least 3 days a week. They&#39;re mostly shorter runs for now, but, hopefully, I will meet or exceed my goal (TBA) when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, my accountability group has been great in pushing me forward. They helped me analyze some of what was going through my mind the last time I wrote. You can help be a part of my accountability by reaching out to me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lgwapnitsky&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://telegram.me/larrygwapnitsky&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, or find me on other social media.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Hot Triple Snack Round-Up: Chana Jor Garam, Ghost Pepper Potato Chips, and Hot Shrimp Crackers</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-16-hot-snack-roundup/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/snacks/spicy_pepper_toon.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/snacks/spicy_pepper_toon.png"/>
		<updated>2021-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-16-hot-snack-roundup/</id>
		<summary>A few trips to different markets and I &#39;bagged&#39; myself a few new snacks to try out. What did I get, and how did they taste?</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;chana-jor-garam&quot;&gt;Chana Jor Garam &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-16-hot-snack-roundup/#chana-jor-garam&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop #1 was at my favorite Indian grocery store. I&#39;m telling you, I have a LOT of trouble leaving this place without browsing the snack aisle. This snack stuck out at me like a sore thumb due to the color of the bag (most of the surrounding ones were yellow).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/images/posts/snacks/chana_jor_garam_front.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One quick look at the ingredients on the back, and I knew I was set - this one had some nice flavors, including mango powder and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asafoetida&quot;&gt;asafoetida&lt;/a&gt; - one of my favorite Indian spices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual snack was smaller than I expected, but boy, were these full of flavor. I can&#39;t even begin to describe the wonderful melding of flavors that were now in my mouth. My buddy, the Musical Mathemetician, had a great description - &amp;quot;a simple chip, not overly complex, yet still brings a lot of flavor to the table.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/images/posts/snacks/chana_jor_garam_photo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I get these again? Probably, and I&#39;d put them in a bowl to serve as a snack at a party. They&#39;re different, but in a great way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;herr&#39;s-ghost-pepper-potato-chips&quot;&gt;Herr&#39;s Ghost Pepper Potato Chips &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-16-hot-snack-roundup/#herr&#39;s-ghost-pepper-potato-chips&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop, Ocean State Job Lot. Here, the snack aisles are stacked with boxes and boxes of chips, but these were highlighted on an end-cap. Ghost pepper? Don&#39;t mind if I do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/images/posts/snacks/herrs_ghost_pepper.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right out of the bag, I knew these were going to have some kick. The smell was powerful of ghost peppers, and the heat was definitely there on my tongue. Was it hot? Yes, but not so much where I couldn&#39;t stuff handfuls into my mouth and enjoy them. Then again, I&#39;m a bit of a heat freak. There was no way anyone else in the family was going to try these, so I got to enjoy the whole bag myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d consider these again, but they&#39;re mostly a fad. Maybe if I had a bunch of people over who I knew enjoyed hot foods I&#39;d pick them up, but I wouldn&#39;t go out of my way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;nongshim-spicy-shrimp-crackers&quot;&gt;Nongshim Spicy Shrimp Crackers &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-16-hot-snack-roundup/#nongshim-spicy-shrimp-crackers&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop 3 - Asian Grocery #1. I love shrimp chips and shrimp crackers. I definitely go out of my way to enjoy them, but I&#39;ve never noticed the spicy ones in the store. Once I saw these, there was no question they were going in my cart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/images/posts/snacks/shrimp_crackers.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not say these were a disappointment. They definitely tasted good. In fact, one of the better brands of shrimp crackers I&#39;ve ever had. Yet, the spice wasn&#39;t really there. Yes, they had a VERY mild kick, but definitely not what I would call spicy. Even my daughter tried and enjoyed them, and she doesn&#39;t do spicy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are a buy-again item, no question asked.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Pause and Effect</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-14-pause-and-effect/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/pause_button.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/pause_button.png"/>
		<updated>2021-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-14-pause-and-effect/</id>
		<summary>What happened in the first 2 weeks of the year that cause me to temporarily pause my workouts? While partially physical, most of it was mental. Here&#39;s the next steps...</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m going to be completely honest...I don&#39;t like working out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, working out is something I need to do not only to help improve my phsyical fitness, but also my mental fitness. Both lead down the road to improved overall wellness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that this year started off a bit rough is an understatement. I&#39;ve been dealing with a pinched nerve in my shoulder, which effects my right arm down to my hand. Thanks to the wonderful care of my chiropractor, it&#39;s been improving significantly, but it&#39;s still taking its time. This has affected my ability to work out using my arms. Considering most of my workout equipment (resistance bands, Bosu ball, Swiss balls) requires some use of the hands and arms, exercising has been short and painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did start hitting the dreadmill a bit again, as well. Due to increased weight and lack of consistent exercise over an extended period of time, I&#39;m finding myself winded quicker over much shorter distances. In my short workouts, I&#39;ve yet to break the .75 mile mark. This is a long stretch from the guy who &amp;quot;ran&amp;quot; a marathon in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These things combined with other issues (some related to the pandemic) have set me back a bit mentally. I&#39;m finding lower motivation in my life to exercise. I&#39;ve checked in with my accountability group, and they&#39;re great at pushing me, but it&#39;s when I push back that&#39;s the problem. We&#39;re all struggling in one way or another, so I know I&#39;m not alone. I just need to start allowing their pushing to knock me down to the point where I want to get back up on my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said in the beginning, I&#39;m going to be open about stuff, so here I am laying it out. Want to help me be accountable? Want to help me be motivated? Feel free to reach out to me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lgwapnitsky&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, hit me up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://telegram.me/larrygwapnitsky&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, or find me on other social media.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Weight Is Over...By A Lot</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-04-the-weight-is-over/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/health/scale.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/health/scale.png"/>
		<updated>2021-01-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-04-the-weight-is-over/</id>
		<summary>Restarting the fitness journey, I decided to step on the scale this morning. What I saw was not what I wanted, so it&#39;s time to aim for my goals.</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Overall fitness improvement is the goal for not just this year, but the future in general. I&#39;m not going to set time- or weight-specific goals, as those have caused me to struggle mentally in the past. What I DO want to do is lower my weight to a more healthy range and get my physical activity back up to a reasonable state so that I can be active without getting tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this combined starts today,  January 4th, 2021 (well, actually last night). I began doing intermittent fasting again using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zerofasting.com/&quot;&gt;Zero&lt;/a&gt; as my tracker and guide. I have my fitness apps all set to go, as well as videos I&#39;ve made note of on YouTube. In addition, I&#39;ve already spoken to the guys in my accountability group, and we&#39;re all in this together. I believe that last part is what&#39;s going to really push me through this year, as the intent is to really be accountable to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&#39;s plan - continue my fast and get a little exercise and meditation in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you plan to follow me on this journey, don&#39;t expect the use of the word &lt;em&gt;diet&lt;/em&gt; or specific mentions of actual body weight. What you can expect is to see updates on how I&#39;m feeling mentally about the physical changes and (hopeful) improvements that are coming. Drop me a line on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lgwapnitsky&quot;&gt;@lgwapnitsky&lt;/a&gt; with words of encouragement, inspiration, or if you want accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/8y8NVqFqhTQVa&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowFullScreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/gifs/ratatouille-admin-billy-boyd-8y8NVqFqhTQVa&quot;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Chips of deception - Tteokbokki</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-03-hot-chip-deception-tteokbokki/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/snacks/tteokbokki_front_rotated.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/snacks/tteokbokki_front_rotated.png"/>
		<updated>2021-01-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-03-hot-chip-deception-tteokbokki/</id>
		<summary>Looked hot...was not. Going by the packaging alone, I expected these to kill my tastebuds, but mild disappointment was all I got.</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tteokbokki is well-known as a spicy Korean street food - long, tubular rice cakes with a sauce made traditionally from gochujang and anchove-based broth. Considering how spicy it can be served on the street, this snack, once I looked it up after buying it, should have been good and spicy. Even without looking it up, the picture of the smiling hot pepper on the front, and the inclusion of capsaicin powder in the ingredients should have been a good marker pointing to lots of spice. It even says &amp;quot;HOT SPICE&amp;quot; on the back!! Well...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/images/posts/snacks/tteokbokki_back_800_rotated.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon opening the bag, there was a hint of spice, but nothing overpowering. Not a good sign to start. I poured some out and started to munch on them. If anything, there was more of a sweetness than a spiciness. I waited and, eventually, there was a little bit of spice, but nothing that warranted the &amp;quot;warning signs&amp;quot; from the labels. I gave some to my daughter, who doesn&#39;t like spice, and she really liked these...again, because of the sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I recommend thse? Only if you like sweet and spicy, leaning more toward the sweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess my next step is to learn how to recreate the real thing...not the crispy bagged snack. Once that happens, I&#39;ll be sure to update you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>A Very Happy New Year To You</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-01-Happy-New-Year/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/happy-new-year-2021-new-820x554.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/happy-new-year-2021-new-820x554.png"/>
		<updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-01-Happy-New-Year/</id>
		<summary>What&#39;s in store for me in the coming year? How do I plan to educate and improve myself?</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Without going into too much detail, the past year-plus has been very difficult for me. My fitness has waned significantly, my mental acuity has suffered, and I&#39;ve just not felt very self-confident. I&#39;m sure many others have felt this with the overwhelming power that COVID-19 has had over our society. I&#39;m not saying I&#39;m a unique butterfly, but my issues are mine to address, and only mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;physical-fitness&quot;&gt;Physical Fitness &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-01-Happy-New-Year/#physical-fitness&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many races were postponed or cancelled in 2020 due to the pandemic. Combined with a lack of mental energy, I completely fell off in my workout routines, gained some weight (which I did try to work on and made some progress regarding loss), and have physically changed back to an uncomfortable level. I did try to lean on my social groups, but this proved to be difficult to manage, even though we were accountable to each other. As a runner, and general fitness guy, this has not sat well with me, and I need a good kick in the butt to get going again. How? More accountability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m going to lay myself bare, here. I&#39;m going to update you on my physical progress as the year goes on. While it may not be frequent, I&#39;ll try at least once per month to let you know where I am in terms of setting/following a routine and how I&#39;m feeling. If I fall short on posting, call me out on social media. If I&#39;m slacking off and losing motivation, call me out on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the goal is to use my physical fitness to build routines that will eventually help build and improve on my...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mental-fitness&quot;&gt;Mental Fitness &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-01-Happy-New-Year/#mental-fitness&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that managing my mental fitness in 2020 has been a tough row to hoe is an understatement. I struggled with keeping my mind active, trying to read, avoiding useless video media, and wasting time on the Internet. I know that I can do better, it&#39;s just a matter of setting the habits and goals, then sticking to them. Much like physical fitness, I need the accountability and tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to journal this year, then gave up within a matter of days. The book is sitting by my bedside. Restart it? Use the blog as a &amp;quot;journal&amp;quot; of sorts? Possibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a lot of work ahead in order to regain the fitness I once had, much like my physical fitness. Will I ever be the same? Probably not. Can I be a better version of who I&#39;ve been for the past year? Definitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-growth-%26-education&quot;&gt;Personal Growth &amp;amp; Education &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-01-Happy-New-Year/#personal-growth-%26-education&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I&#39;ll review my past goals and set some new ones here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many cooking-related goals to review and set:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grilling and smoking - I learned to make pastrami this year. That was an adventure, and pretty darned delicious. Beyond that, I just smoked meats when I felt like it, but didn&#39;t quite do enough. So, for 2021, the goal is to smoke more more meat AND to continue building my own smoker (soon to be written about in The Lab), which coincides with another goal for the year that will be mentioned below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CEudcFtHmGe&quot;&gt;https://www.instagram.com/p/CEudcFtHmGe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sous-vide and pickling went hand-in-hand, as I used my SV for pickling, as well as some delicious fish, scallops, and beautiful strip steaks. Again, the goal is to do more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pressure cooker has been my go-to for a few years, now, and this year I really picked up on some new dishes that became family favorites - meatloaf &amp;amp; mashed potatoes, pork belly with shoyu eggs, and more. 2021 is the year of learning to bake in the pressure cooker. I&#39;ve tried once with middling success. I REALLY want to make a cheesecake!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just keep cooking! It&#39;s fun, I&#39;m learning a lot, especially with baking AND the fact that my son is gluten-free, so adjusting for that has been an adventure in learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-learn programming - why? Well, for one, I need it for my smoker. I&#39;m combining a few projects and building a smoker out of a file-cabinet, then adding in a temperature regulated heater to manage the smoke temperature. As of writing this, I&#39;m 75% done with the cabinet, and about 80% with the electronics. The latter is the tougher part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to meet my Goodreads reading goal this year, with a few cheat books included that I read to my daughter. I don&#39;t see an option for a 2021 challenge, but my plan is to either meet or exceed the 52 books completed in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;gr_challenge_11621&quot; style=&quot;border: 2px solid #EBE8D5; border-radius:10px; padding: 0px 7px 0px 7px; max-width:230px; min-height: 100px&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div id=&quot;gr_challenge_progress_body_11621&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 12px; font-family: georgia,serif;line-height: 18px&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 4px 0 10px; font-weight: normal; text-align: center&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-family:georgia,serif;font-style:italic; font-size: 1.1em&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/challenges/11621-2020-reading-challenge&quot;&gt;2020 Reading Challenge&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h3&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;challengePic&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/challenges/11621-2020-reading-challenge&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;2020 Reading Challenge&quot; style=&quot;float:left; margin-right: 10px; border: 0 none&quot; src=&quot;https://images.gr-assets.com/challenges/1575497947p2/11621.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/1656256-larry&quot;&gt;Larry&lt;/a&gt; has
            completed his goal of reading
            50 books in
            2020!
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div style=&quot;width: 100px; margin: 4px 5px 5px 0; float: left; border: 1px solid #382110; height: 8px; overflow: hidden; background-color: #FFF&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&quot;width: 100%; background-color: #D7D2C4; float: left&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;visibility:hidden&quot;&gt;hide&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div style=&quot;font-family: arial, verdana, helvetica, sans-serif;font-size:90%&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/19222365&quot;&gt;52 of 50 (100%)&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a style=&quot;text-decoration: none; font-size: 10px;&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/19222365&quot;&gt;view books&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;script src=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/widget/1656256-larry?challenge_id=11621&amp;v=2&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-of-the-iceberg&quot;&gt;Tip of the Iceberg &lt;a class=&quot;direct-link&quot; href=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2021-01-01-Happy-New-Year/#tip-of-the-iceberg&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only just the beginning. 2021 is really the year I want to make changes, as well as be mindful of and accountable to them. I hope you&#39;ll join me on the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>The Chips Are On The Table/Hot Tikha Ganthia</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2020-12-22-the-chips-are-on-the-table/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/snacks/tikha_ganthia_bag.png"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/snacks/tikha_ganthia_bowl_HDR.png"/>
		<updated>2020-12-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2020-12-22-the-chips-are-on-the-table/</id>
		<summary>I do most of the shopping for the family, making as few trips as possible due to the pandemic. Therefore, I get to choose some of the fun treats that get brought home occasstionally. My new habit is to find interesting-flavored snacks from around the world and try them. So, why not write about them?</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite types of place to shop is ethnic supermarkets. I had a need for a lot of very specific ingredients for some cooking that I was going, so I schlepped to my local Indian market to grab what I needed. While wandering around, I stubmled into the snack aisle and became overwhelmed with the selection of interesting flavors. One type of flavor that always sticks out to me (and will become somewhat of a running theme) is hot and spicy. So when I saw bags upon bags of spicy snacks, I knew that I had to try something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some browsing at the amazing selection, I decided on a bag of Tikha Ganthia. These are spicy little chickpea flour noodles. They looked like crunchy, curvy sticks of flavor, and I was sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/images/posts/snacks/tikha_ganthia_bag.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opened the bag when I got home to have with lunch, and I knew that, from aroma alone, I was going to like these. There was a warm spiciness that I&#39;ve come to expect from good quality Indian food. I poured some into a bowl, and dug in. These are defintely not the snacks we&#39;re used to here in the United States.  The use of chickpea flour is also unique to my tastebuds for snacks.  The crunch was subdued, but had the perfect amount of mouth-feel. The flavor, while spicy, was not overwhelming. Then again, I have a hot pallette and usually eat hotter than normal foods that my family doesn&#39;t care for (bonus, these chips are now all mine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://larry.wapnitsky.com/images/posts/snacks/tikha_ganthia_bowl_HDR.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I buy these again? In a heartbeat.&lt;br /&gt;
Would I recommend them? Absolutely!&lt;br /&gt;
Am I going to try to learn how to make a homemade version? Time will tell...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>I&#39;m back to blogging</title>
		<link href="https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2020-12-15-back-to-blogging/"/>
		<link rel="icon" href="/images/posts/reset-300x234.jpg"/>
		<link rel="preview" href="/images/posts/reset-300x234.jpg"/>
		<updated>2020-12-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://larry.wapnitsky.com/posts/2020-12-15-back-to-blogging/</id>
		<summary>It&#39;s been a while since I&#39;ve worked on my blog, but there&#39;s no better time than now to refresh the way it looks and to start writing again.</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Overall, it should be good for my mind to wipe away the cobwebs and be creative. But what&#39;s been keeping me from writing all this time, and what plans do I have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t really decided on a single path, but there&#39;s be a good mix of cooking and food stuff, technology, my journey back into fitness, home projects, and more. There&#39;s so much in my mind that it&#39;s tough to figure out exactly where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, short post to (re)start things off, but I really hope to keep myself on track this time and keep blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larry&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
